Guide to the Dams, papers concerning design and construction, 1903-1956
Department of Special Collections
Dams, papers concerning design and construction,
1903-1956
Special Collections M0435
Durand, William F.; Atkinson, Lynn
3 linear ft. (30 items)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Transfer from the Engineering Library stacks and historical collection, 1985. Various previous sources, including William F. Durand and Lynn Atkinson.
Scope and Content
Summary: Design and construction reports on and photographs of several major United States dams, including: Boulder, Coolidge, Friant, Grand Coulee, and Hoover.
Container List
- Ambursen Dams, 1903-1913, Ambursen Hydraulic Construction Company). (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Boulder Dam
  - J. L. Savage (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Colorado River Storage. Boulder Canyon Project. Memorandum to consulting board, 1929.
  - J. L. Savage (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Present status of Boulder Canyon Designs, 1930.
  - William F. Durand's papers concerning Boulder Dam, 1935. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Company. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Drawings of Boulder Canyon Project, 1935.
  - Charles P. Berkey (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Report on seismic disturbances at Boulder Dam, 1939.
  - George A. Pettitt (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - So Boulder Dam was Built, [1956?]
  - Boulder Dam, photographs, Vol. 1, 1932-1934. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Boulder Dam, photographs, Vol. 2, 1934-1935. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boulder Dam, photographs, Vol. 3, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Boulder Dam, construction progress. Photographs, 1933. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Coolidge Dam
  - Atkinson, Kier Bros., Spicer Co. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Construction of the Coolidge Dam, San Carlos, Arizona. 1927-28.
- Friant Dam
  - U.S. Bureau of Reclamation (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Memorandum to Board of Consultants, Friant Dam, Friant, Calif. 1914.
- Grand Coulee Dam
  - Charles P. Berkey, et al. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Report on the Geological Investigations of the Grand Coulee Reservoir, 1940.
  - R. L. Nichols (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Memorandum on progress of water-table investigation around south damsite, 1941.
  - R. L. Nichols (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Progress report -- Investigations on Grand Coulee since last board report, 1941.
  - U.S. Bureau of Reclamation (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Concrete control report for consulting board, 1941.
  - R. L. Nichols (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Water tests on drill holes..., 1941.
  - R. L. Nichols (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Supplemental maps and cross sections, 1942.
- Hoover Dam
  - U.S. Bureau of Reclamation (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hoover Dam -- compilation of data..., 1930.
  - U.S. Bureau of Reclamation (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Supplement to above, 1931.
  - Board of Consulting Engineers on concrete problems for Hoover Dam, 1931. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ransome, F. L. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Report on the geology of the Hoover Dam site and vicinity, 1931.
  - Progress report to the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation on the Hoover Dam concrete research, 1932. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Company (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
    - Reports of tests of pipe and fittings for Hoover dam project, 1932., (3 v.)
  - Raymond E. Davis (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Cement investigations for Hoover Dam, 1932.
  - Raymond E. Davis (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Cement investigations for Hoover Dam, 1933.
- Pardee Dam
  - Atkinson Construction Company (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Construction of the Pardee Dam, 1927-1929.Photograph album.